Guide to the Davenport College and Pierson College, Yale University, Photographs
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Davenport College and Pierson College, Yale University, photographs
1930-1961
RU 600
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6
The collection contains photographs, slides, and pictures of Davenport College and Pierson College at Yale. Included are interior and exterior views, views of the masters" houses, dining halls, and courtyards, as well as photographs documenting construction.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 46-B (YRG 46-B), Records and materials documenting individual Yale buildings, facilities, and grounds.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains photographs, slides, and pictures of Davenport College and Pierson College at Yale. Included are interior and exterior views, views of the masters' houses, dining halls, and courtyards, as well as photographs documenting construction.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged in two series: I. Construction Progress Photographs, 1930-1932. II. General Views, circa 1930-1969.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
College buildings -- Design and construction; Photographs; Slides (photographs); Davenport College (Yale University); Pierson College (Yale University); Yale University -- Pictorial works; Yale University -- Buildings; Yale University -- Student housing
- Construction progress photographs, 1930 - 1932; Series I
  - Pre-Construction (pre-demolition site views), 1930 June (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Excavation, 1930 August-October (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Construction, 1930 November- 1932 September (Box 1, Folder 3 - 12)
  - Completed exterior (Box 1, Folder 13)
- General views, circa 1930 - 1961; Series II
  - General construction views, Davenport and Pierson, circa 1930 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Davenport College
    - Construction, general, circa1930, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 2 - 5)
    - York Street facade, 1931-1933, n.d (Box 2, Folder 6 - 7)
    - Courtyard, general, 1930, n.d (Box 2, Folder 8 - 10)
    - Courtyard B East wall, 1934-1939, n.d (Box 2, Folder 11 - 13)
    - Courtyard B North wall, 1944-1935, n.d (Box 2, Folder 14 - 15)
    - Colonnade and passageways, 1936-1937, n.d (Box 2, Folder 16 - 18)
    - Master"s garden, undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Interior B common room, 1961, n.d (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Interior B library, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Interior B dining hall, 1930-1940, n.d (Box 2, Folder 22 - 25)
    - Foor plan (architect"s drawing), undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Pierson College
    - Construction, general (negatives), 1931 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Construction views, general, 1930- 1932 (Box 2, Folder 28-30)
    - General, 1931-1937, n.d (Box 2, Folder 31 - 34)
    - A Slave Quarters, 1934, 1937, n.d (Box 2, Folder 35 - 38)
    - Tower, 1931-1939, n.d (Box 2, Folder 39 - 42)
    - Master"s House, exterior, Park Street, undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Master"s House, interior, undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Walkways and gateways, 1937-1938, n.d (Box 2, Folder 45 - 47)
    - Park Street Gate, undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Interior B dining hall, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Interior B library, undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Elevation (architect's drawing), undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Oversize, slides and transparencies, Series III
  - Oversize
    - Davenport College (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Slides
    - Davenport College (Box 4)
    - Pierson College (Box 4)
  - Transparencies
    - Pierson College, exterior (Box 5)
    - Pierson College, exterior (Box 5)
    - A Slave Quarters (Box 5)
    - Pierson-Davenport (Box 5)
  - Folio
    - Construction, from top of University Theatre (Box DR24F78)
    - Site of Pierson, 253 Park, [prior to 1930] (Box DR24F78)
    - Site of Pierson, circa 1924 (Box DR24F78)